E-Friends

<p><word pos="pronoun" headword="there">There</word> <word pos="verb" headword="be">was</word> <word pos="adverb">once</word> <word pos="article">a</word> <word pos="noun">time</word> <word pos="conjunction">when</word> <word pos="determiner">most</word> <word pos="noun">people</word> <word pos="verb" headword="grow up">grew up</word>, <word pos="verb" headword="live">lived</word>, <word pos="conjunction">and</word> <word pos="verb" headword="die">died</word> <word pos="preposition">in</word> <word pos="conjunction">or</word> <word pos="preposition">near</word> <word pos="article">the</word> <word pos="noun">community</word> <word pos="conjunction">where</word> <word pos="pronoun">they</word> <word pos="verb" headword="be">were</word> <word pos="adjective">born</word>.  <word pos="noun" headword="men">Men</word> <word pos="verb" headword="be">were</word> <word pos="adjective" headword="likely">most likely</word> <word pos="verb" headword="take up">to take up</word> <word pos="pronoun">their</word> <word pos="noun" headword="father">fathers'</word> <word pos="noun">profession</word>.</p> 

<p>Technology, however, has completely changed the notions of workplace and home.  Increased mobility and job insecurity have scattered families across states, countries and continents.  Whereas the average college-educated American in 1950 would expect to work for one or two companies his whole life, Americans now average 8 major employers in their lifetimes and two to three careers.</p>

<p>The lightning fast pace of technology creates jobs seemingly out of thin air and then, just as quickly, renders jobs as obsolete as the eight track.  Increasingly workers are asked to market themselves, to continue re-educating themselves, and to update their skills in order to keep up with the runaway train of progress.</p>

<p>The Internet has become a double--edged sword keeping us connected to friends left behind in past jobs and cities, while at the same time blurring the lines between work and family, private and public.  This new globally connected economy makes it so your coworkers are just as likely to live in Calcutta as in the cubicle next to yours.  In such a world where our central means of communication is likely to be a modem, what defines community?</p>

